# Nimesh Solanki

Accountants & Online Marketing

# Contact

**Address** 

Ahmedabad, GJ, 380061

**Phone** 

903 382 0682

E-mail

nimesh.solanki97@gmail.co m

**Twitter** 

@nimesh04140915

# **Skills**

Managing accounts

Creating accounts

Accounts reconciliation

Finalization of accounts

Sales expertise

Online sales & Email conversation

Orders & payments followups

Precise Accounts Payable Specialist with 6 years of experience working with accounts. Skilled at fixing account and data discrepancies with professionalism and using Tally ERP 9. Proven history of resourcefulness, accuracy and extensive knowledge of Accounts and sales.

# **Work History**

## 2018-06 -Current

#### **ACCOUNTS & SALES**

Industrial products pvt Itd

- Maintained clean and organized files by keeping accounts payable records up-to-date.
- Entered financial data into company accounting database for verification and reconciliation, maintaining accurate and current accounts at all times.
- Used Tally ERP 9 Software to accurately manage over account.
- Managed and updated financial accounts and permanent records for more than 190 current clients.
- Reduced financial discrepancies, effectively reconciling bank accounts and organizing information into accounting software.
- Complied with all established policies and performed bank reconciliations, accounts payable/receivable, invoicing, billing, collections, balance records, vendor payments and profit and loss statements for 190 clients.
- Prepared and mailed invoices to customers, processed payments and documented account updates.
- Assisted day staff by completing daily computer backups, virus checks and program updates.
- Daily phone call to customer for the orders and payment.
- Make the quotations according to clients requirement and send by E-mail with technical details / catalog,
- Followups to clients for inquiry status and orders status by E-mail and phone calls.
- To make the Test certificates of products and provides to clients,

Technical discussion of products

Serch new buyer online

# Software

Tally ERP 9

MS office with word, excel & power point

**Email conversation** 

Photo shop

Adobe reader

Paint

- Finalization with clients for the project orders.
- To make the festival greetings on behalf of company and post in social media for digital marketing purpose.
- Daily send gental reminder mail to client for the inquiry status purpose.
- New product upload in website with post new offers in company website.
- New Vendor registration procedure.
- Inquiry/quotation/technical/invoicing/payment/disp atch arrangement whole procedure followups with clients.

## 2013-04 -2018-05

#### **Accountants**

RHT PHARMACEUTICALS PRIVATE LIMITED, SARKHEJ, GUJARAT

- Helped clients navigate interactions with tax authorities and legal concerns related to financial matters.
- Completed daily cash functions like account tracking, payroll and wage allocations, budgeting, donating and all types of cash and banking reconciliations.
- Collected and arranged financial information and entered details into PDIS+ financial management system.
- Supported monthly reporting analysis to achieve validation of internal reports and to reconcile production operations and general ledger.
- Managed entire accounting cycle including gathering information, preparing documents, finalizing reports and closing books.
- Maintained up-to-date knowledge on permits, certificates and documents mandatory for government departments.
- Reconciled accounts and reviewed all materials, including surplus, income, expense data, net worth and assets.
- Accurately documented all cash, credit, fixed assets, accrued expenses and line of credit transactions.

# Education

2013-04 -	Master of Commerce
2016-06	Gujarat University - Chanakyapuri
2009-06 - 2012-03	Bachelor of Commerce
	Gujarat Commerce College - Ellisbridge Ahmedabad